Love is a burning thing.
Walk the Line is a drama, music, romance film directed by James Mangold.
A chronicle of country music legend Johnny Cash's life, from his early days on an Arkansas cotton farm to his rise to fame
with Sun Records in Memphis, where he recorded alongside Elvis Presley, Jerry Lee Lewis and Carl Perkins.
John R. Cash, played by Joaquin Phoenix.
June Carter, played by Reese Witherspoon.
Vivian Cash, played by Ginnifer Goodwin.
Ray Cash, played by Robert Patrick.
Sam Phillips, played by Dallas Roberts.
Luther Perkins, played by Dan John Miller.
Walk the Line is a 2005 American biographical
drama film directed by James Mangold.
The screenplay, written by Mangold and Gill Dennis, is based on two autobiographies by the American singer-songwriter
Johnny Cash:  Man in Black: His Own Story in His Own Words (1975) and Cash: The Autobiography (1997).
The film follows Cash's early life, his romance with the singer June Carter,
his ascent in the country music scene, and his drug addiction.
It stars Joaquin Phoenix as Cash, Reese Witherspoon as Carter, Ginnifer Goodwin as
Cash's first wife Vivian Liberto, and Robert Patrick as Cash's father.
Walk the Line premiered at the Telluride Film Festival on September 4, 2005, and
was theatrically released by  20th Century Fox on November 18.
It received positive reviews and was a  box office success,
grossing $187 million on a $28 million budget.
At the 78th Academy Awards, Witherspoon won Best Actress while the film was also nominated for
Best Actor (Phoenix), Best Sound Mixing, Best Costume Design and Best Film Editing.
The film explores themes of prison, adultery,
concert, music record, country music.
The tone is emotional.